Email: flojo8584@gmail.com Phone: +91 8754812600

D. FLORA ANNIE MARY

Senior Human Resources -Talent Acquisition -Recruitment Professional Chennai, India.

Over the past **9 years**, till now working in the field of Recruitment towards **IT and Non IT, Recruitment-Recruitment Trainer, Team Lead Talent Acquisition, Business Development, Client Relationships.**

Contribution of work in IT and Not Domains towards recruitment management towards team also individual contributor in sourcing, screening shortlisting, scheduling interviews till on boarding. Managed client relationship involved in business development, recruitment training etc

In the 9 years of recruitment travel handled different domains towards IT recruitment Permanent staffing, Contract staffing. RPO for all the hierarchy positions for MNC 's and other companies and Non – IT Recruitments. As a Talent Acquisition – Lead /Senior Recruiter satisfy the requirements to complete on TAT(Turn Around Time). Recruitment Trainer- Handled training sessions for the Junior Recruiters for Screening, Sourcing in all Job portals, Head Hunting, Employee Referrals, Mock calls and LinkedIn -X Ray or Boolean Search.

IT Positions Handled- Data Architect, Technical Lead, Senior 7 Junior Software Developers, Cloud Architect, Solution Architect, Web Development, Web Application Developer etc almost all positions top to bottom Technologies: Java, python, HTML, CSS, perl, javascript, Laravel, tableau, Einstein Analytics, Power BI, ETL, Qlik Sense, Dot net, Azure, AWS, GCP almost all technologies involved

Non IT- IT Hardware, Networkning, CISCO, Auto Ancillary Etc almost many positions handles in career

Seeking a challenging and growth-oriented career where I can utilize my skills and knowledge with the opportunity for professional growth and to excel by contributing towards the achievement of organizational goals.

SKILLS

Languages Known: English and Tamil Proficiency - Expert

Technologies Known: SEO and Google Adwords

EMPLOYMENT AND EXPERIENCE

Bloom Solutions- (June 2021 till date) – https://www.bloomsolutions.com/

Designation: Team Lead(Talent Acquisition HR).

Job Responsibilities

- IT Recruitment- All Hierarchies for Top most companies
- Client Coordination
- Recruitment Training

- Team Handling
- Business Development
- Screening, Shortlisting, Interview Scheduling, On Boarding
- RPO
- Conduct Assessments for external clients interview

1. Perfect Recruitment Solutions- (June 2020 - June 2021) hrperfectrs.wixsite.com/timebound-hirings

Designation- Senior IT Recruiter Team Lead

Designation: Team Lead(Talent Acquisition HR).

Job Responsibilities

- IT Recruitment- All Hierarchies for Top most companies
- Client Coordination
- Recruitment Training
- Team Handling
- Screening, Shortlisting, Interview Scheduling, On Boarding

2. Prompt Trade Fairs (March 2017 – December 2019) - https://www.prompttradefairs.com/

Designation: HR Executive-Non IT/Project Coordinator.

Description:

Work on job portals, Social Media, Referrals and New paper advertisement, Job Posting Etc. Shortlist and screen the candidates for internal hiring PAN India. Bulk hiring of candidates when required. Handle all the recruitments for the hierarchies in the domains such as Accounts, Marketing, Designing, and Front Office. Handle Performance appraisal of Employees, Payroll, and Biometric

Responsibilities:

- Recruit Candidates as per the requirements.
- Configure Biometric for employees.
- Employees Training
- Analyze all environments of the company for recruitment, development and training.

3. Reach Management Consultants (June 2015 – October 2015). - http://www.reach.co.in/

Designation: HR Consultant-Non IT Recruitment

Description: Work on job portals, Social Media, Referrals Etc for sourcing resumes. Shortlist and screen the candidates for internal hiring PAN India. Bulk hiring of candidates when required. Handle all the recruitments for the hierarchies in the domains such as Auto, Auto Ancillary, and Insurance for all hierarchies.

Responsibilities:

- Shortlist the candidates according to the JD given
- Work on Job Portals for sourcing Resumes
- Coordinate for Interview with candidates
- Salary Negotiation

4. Prompt Trade Fairs I Pvt Ltd (January 2013 – November 2014)- https://www.prompttradefairs.com/

Designation: HR Executive/ Project Coordinator

Description: Work on job portals, Social Media, Referrals and New paper advertisement, Job Posting Etc. Shortlist and screen the candidates for internal hiring PAN India. Bulk hiring of candidates when required. Handle all the recruitments for the hierarchies in the domains such as Accounts, Marketing, Designing, and Front Office. Handle Performance appraisal of Employees, Payroll, and Biometric

Responsibilities:

- Recruit Candidates as per the requirements.
- Configure Biometric for employees.
- Analyze all environments of the company for recruitment, development and training.

5. Allsec Technologies (November 2010- July 2011).

Designation Quality Analyst

Responsibilities:

Monitor and send report for International voice calls

EDUCATION

Degree Name	University/Board	Passing Year	Result
BE(ECE)	Anna University	July, 2009	65%
DIPLOMA	Department Of Technical Education	April, 2006	89%
SSC	Anglo Indian board	May, 2001	65%

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Date of Birth: 27-12-1985

• Languages Known: English, Tamil

• Marital Status : Married

• Husband Name: D. Joseph Victor

Address: No 3311, MMDA Mathur 75th street, Chennai – 68.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above cited information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Name: D Flora Annie Mary